Guide to the Manley H. Thompson Papers 1939-1998
University of Chicago Library
Thompson, Manley H. Papers
1939-1998
15 linear feet (27 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Manley Hawn Thompson was Professor of Philosophy at the University of Chicago from 1949 to 1987. The collection mostly contains correspondence and drafts of his and others' scholarly writings, dating from 1939 to 1998. The bulk of the material is from the 1980s.
Information on Use
Access
Most of the collection is open for research; however, there are several boxes of material that are restricted for various lengths of time. Folders 1 to 15 of Box 25 are restricted for 25-30 years from the date of creation; Folders 16 to 22 of Box 25 and 1 to 8 of Box 26 are restricted for fifty years from the date of creation; Folders 9 to 18 of Box 26 and all of Box 27 are restricted for eighty years from the date of creation.
Biographical Note
Manley Hawn Thompson was born in Zanesville, Ohio on April 12, 1917. He received both his A.B. and A.M. from the University of Chicago in 1938, and a Ph.D. in philosophy in 1942. Upon completing school, Thompson joined the U.S. Naval reserves, and remained until 1946. After the war, he taught for three years at the University of Toronto before returning to the University of Chicago in 1949 as an Assistant professor in philosophy. With the exception of visiting lectureships and other temporary associations with other universities, Thompson spent the remainder of his career at the University of Chicago.
Thompson married Margaret Phyllis MacKenzie and the couple had three children: Katherine, Roderick, and Clark.
Thompson's early interests centered on C. S. Peirce and, to a lesser extent, American pragmatism more generally. His only book-length work, The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce, was based on his dissertation and published in 1953. Thompson had a general interest in metaphysics and epistemology, particularly that of Immanuel Kant. He was a leading authority on Kant's theory of categories, and at the time of his death, was working on a manuscript dealing with Kant's account of our understanding of mathematical concepts. Thompson also published articles on Aristotle and W. V. O. Quine, semantics and logic. He authored the Metaphysics monograph for the Princeton Studies in Philosophy.
Thompson's professional career included serving on the Harvard philosophy department's visiting committee and as a member of Princeton's Associate Council on the Humanities from 1960 through 1965. He was active in the Aristotelian Society, the C. S. Peirce Society, the North American Kant Society, and was president of the American Philosophical Association in 1983.
Thompson retired from the University of Chicago in 1987. In 1991 he was diagnosed with a form of Parkinson's disease that gradually affected his ability to read and write, though he continued to correspond as much as possible with colleagues and former students. Thompson died in 1994.
Scope Note
The collection is divided into eight series: Personal, Correspondence, Professional Activities, Teaching, Writings, Writings by Others, Oversize, and Restricted. Noted philosophers represented in the Correspondence and Writings by Others series include Henry Allison, Michael Friedman, Paul Guyer, Christine Korsgaard, Richard McKeon, and Sally Sedgwick. There are also brief letters from J. L. Austin, Rudolf Carnap, W. V. O. Quine, and Bertrand Russell.
Series I, Personal, contains a few personal papers of Manley Thompson's and some correspondence belonging to his wife, Phyllis. There are also several folders of newspaper clippings and articles on religious subjects collected by Phyllis, mostly after her husband's death. Manley Thompson's papers are first, followed by Phyllis'; each set is arranged chronologically.
Series II, Correspondence, contains professional correspondence. Thompson corresponded extensively with colleagues and former students, and so some of the material here is of some philosophical substance. Correspondents often included drafts or offprints of their work for comment; in cases where a collection of letters from an individual includes enclosed articles, those articles are included here. As many of Thompson's colleagues and former students are themselves prominent scholars, the series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with general correspondence arranged chronologically at the end. Correspondence regarding and with students at the time of their study is in Series V: Teaching.
Series III, Professional Activities, contains records, correspondence, and papers relating to Thompson's non-instructional professional activities: his service on the Harvard visiting committee, referee reports for journals and academic presses (older than 25 years), grant materials, etc. It also includes material relating to the Kant Society, the Charles Pierce Society, and the American Philosophical Association. Material is arranged chronologically.
Series IV, Writings, contains notes, manuscripts, typescripts, and offprints of Thompsons's academic writing, including materials related to his book, The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce. Materials are arranged chronologically. Part of the mathematics manuscript was written on the back of papers that are currently restricted, so a partial photocopy is included in this series, with the corresponding part of the original in Series VIII.
Series V, Teaching, contains syllabi and course materials, student work (except where restricted), and administrative records. The series is divided into two subseries:
Subseries 1: General: This subseries contains correspondence with and regarding students, their dissertation bits and other student papers, course notes, rosters and syllabi, and administrative material, arranged chronologically.
Subseries 2: Notebooks: This subseries contains bound notebooks with course notes from the 1940s-1980s.
Series VI, Writings by Others, contains drafts and offprints of articles and books by others, including some correspondence and scant handwritten comments by Thompson. Material in the series is alphabetized by author. In cases where the work was accompanied by a letter or two, that correspondence is included here.
Series VII, Oversize, contains complete newspapers and oversize clippings.
Series VIII, Restricted, contains material with various restrictions. Folders 1 to 15 of Box 25 are restricted for 25-30 years from the date of creation; Folders 16 to 22 of Box 25 and 1 to 8 of Box 26 are restricted for fifty years from the date of creation; Folders 9 to 18 of Box 26 and all of Box 27 are restricted for eighty years from the date of creation.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
Browse finding aids by topic.
McKeon, Richard Peter. Papers
Subject Headings
Thompson, Manley Hawn, 1917-; Pierce, Charles S.; University of Chicago. Department of Philosophy; Philosophy
INVENTORY
- Series I: Personal
  - Speed Limit Legislation – Correspondence, Clippings, Congressional Record, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Service Programs – Alan Donagan, Norman Maclean, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Manley Thompson Obituary, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Collected Ephemera (Manley Thompson), 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "A Pastorale of Phyllis" Poem (Photocopy), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Phyllis Thompson – Correspondence – General, 1991-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Phyllis Thompson –Correspondence – Sister Lucy, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Phyllis Thompson – Correspondence – John Dales, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Phyllis Thompson – Religious Materials, Correspondence, Notes on Black Theology, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Phyllis Thompson – Collected Ephemera, 1992-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings Collected by Phyllis Thompson, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Phyllis Thompson – Religious Materials – Photocopies, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Correspondence – Allison, Henry, 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence – American Philosophical Association, 1976-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence – Austin, J. L., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence – Brumbaugh, Bob (includes Article Offprints) [1 of 2], 1946-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence – Brumbaugh, Bob and Ada (includes Article Offprints) [2 of 2], 1981-1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence – Burks, Arthur W. (incl. Article Photocopies), 1957-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence – Buroker, Jill Vance (incl. Papers and Comments), 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence – Carnap, Rudolf, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence – Donagan, Alan, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence – Dreben Burton, 1959-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence – Eldridge, Richard, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence – Ferrell, Brian (incl. Paper Draft), circa 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence – Godlove, Terry, 1982-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence – Greenberg, Robert (incl. Notes, Draft Pages) [1 of 2], 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence – Greenberg, Robert (incl. Paper Drafts) [2 of 2] 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Grant Materials – Guyer, Paul, 1981, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence – Howell, Robert (incl. Offprints and Notes) [1 of 2], 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence – Howell, Robert (incl. Offprints and Notes) [2 of 2], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence – Kahler, Charley, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence – Kim Heisook, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence – Korsgaard, Christine, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence – Laursen, John C. (incl. Articles and Comments) 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence – Lear, Jonathan (incl. Articles), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence – Mandelbaum, Maurice, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence – McKeon, Richard, 1942-1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence – Mosser, Kurt, 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence – re Peirce's Search for a Method, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence – Posy, Carl J. (incl. Article Offprints), 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence – Quine, W. V. O. (incl. Draft), 1969-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence – Roth, Paul A. (incl. Article Drafts), 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence – Russell, Bertrand (Pasch, Weiss, and Quine), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence – Sedgwick, Sally (incl. Paper Drafts) [1 of 2], 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence – Sedgwick, Sally [2 of 2], 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence – Singer, Marcus G., 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence – Wilson, Kirk D. (incl. Paper Drafts) [1 of 2], 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence – Wilson, Kirk D. (incl. Paper Drafts) [2 of 2], 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence – General, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence – General, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence – General, 1956-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence – General, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence – General, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence – General, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence – General, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence – General, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence – General, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence – General, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series III: Professional Activities
  - PhD Comprehensive Exam Questions Secondary Reading List, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fellowship Award, Personnel Record, circa 1941 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Peirce Society – Correspondence, Society Notices, Paper Abstracts, 1947-1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Reviews and Book Notes for Journal Ethics – Typescripts, Galleys, Correspondence, 1949-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reader Reports and Related Correspondence, 1953-1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Philosophy Phollies – Program, Letter, 1954-1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Aristotelian Society – Correspondence and Receipts, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Harvard Visiting Committee – Correspondence, Review Materials, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Professional Directories – Invitations and Bios, 1963-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Conference on the Princeton Studies in the Humanities – Correspondence, Programs, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - X-Club and Innominates: Member Lists, Memos, 1969-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Transactions of the Charles S. Peirce Society – Correspondence, Reviewer's Reports, 1969-1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Math Workbook: Conic Sections, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Review of Metaphysics – Correspondence, Referee Report, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence – Library of Living Philosophers, Whine Volume, 1972-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Peirce Edition Project – Correspondence, Preface, Article Photocopies, Peirce MS photocopy, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - NY State Doctoral Project – Rating Committee – Correspondence and Memos, 1976-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy Research Archives – Correspondence, Referee Reports, 1976-1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Harvard University Overseer's Committee Report – Correspondence, Review Materials, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Harvard Visiting Committee – Correspondence, Reports, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Matters of the Mind" Conference – Papers by Rorty, Parfit, Dennett, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Hartshorne Conference: Paper Drafts (Manuscript and Typescript), Hartshorne Offprints, circa 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - American Philosophical Association – Minutes, Memos, Records, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - American Philosophical Association – Guidelines for Nonsexist Use of Language" – Draft, Memos, Minutes, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Hartshorne Conference and Book: Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Articles – Arthur Burks Festschrift, 1981-1989 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Grant Review – Ameriks, Karl, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Visiting Committee – Correspondence, Guidelines, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society – Journal, Peirce Review, Note, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sixth International Kant Congress – Correspondence, Abstracts, Conference Materials, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Warner Wick Tribute, Obituary, Poem, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Peirce Edition Project – Correspondence, Project Description, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Beta Theta Pi – Membership Card, Ephemera, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Cambridge Edition of Kant – Advisory Board – Correspondence, Contents, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - North American Kant Society – Correspondence, Constitution, Records, 1986-1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - de Pierris, Graciela – Tenure Review Materials, Correspondence (open), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - North American Kant Society – Newsletters and Bibliographies, 1987-1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Kant Conference Papers, Handout (Friedman, Sedgwick), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Recent Perspectives on Kant" – Conference Honoring Thompson – Programs, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - North American Kant Society – Iowa Conference Brochure, Papers [1 of 5], 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - North American Kant Society – Iowa Conference Papers [2 of 5], 1989 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - North American Kant Society – Iowa Conference Papers [3 of 5], 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - North American Kant Society – Iowa Conference Papers [4 of 5], 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - North American Kant Society – Iowa Conference Papers [5 of 5], 1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Continental/Anglo-American Philosophy Conference – Papers and Program, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters and Notes: Kant to Rehberg, Kant to Schultz, Thompson's Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Kant Reflections Excerpts, Geometry Proofs, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Early Analytic Philosophy Conference Honoring Leonard Linsky – Program, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Teaching
  - Subseries 1: General
    - Annual Reports to the Philosophy Department, Notes, 1953-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kant's Dialectic Seminars – Class Lists, Correspondence, Notes, 1977-1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cliff Cornelius (student) – Paper and Correspondence, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Phil 475: Kant's Critique of Pure Reason – Syllabi, Class Lists, Student Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Kent, William P. – "Aristotle on the Science of Mathematics" (M.A. Thesis) – Bound Typescript, letter, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Pamela Lau – Partial Dissertation Drafts, circa 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Dissertation Abstract – Heisook Kim, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Asdell, William – Dissertation Chapter Drafts, Letter, 1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Mosser, Kurt – Dissertation Draft (Chapter 1), Note, photocopies, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Mosser, Kurt – Dissertation Draft (Introduction, Chapter 1, 2), Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Mosser, Kurt – Dissertation Draft (chapter 3) – Typescript, Notes, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Notebooks
    - Notebook – Course Notes: Phil 307, 328, 318, 204, GP, Meta, 1948-1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Notebook – Course Notes: Phil 329, 142, 301, 331, 1952-1960 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Notebook – Course Notes: Phil 439, 339, 232, 416, 131H, 1953, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Notebook – Course Notes: Phil 383, 307, 1962, 1965, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Notebook – Course Notes: Phil 230, 349, 363, 542, 1968-1973, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Notebook – Course Notes: Phil 301, 347, 440, 249, 1970-1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Notebook – Course Outlines/Notes: Phil 442 (III, IV), 476, 540, 577, 1971-1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Notebook – Course Notes: Phil 419, 449, 319, 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Notebook – Course Outlines/Notes: Phil 380/475, 280, 262, 275, 1972-1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Notebook – Course Notes: Phil 383-485, 301, 351, 1975-1983 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Notebook – Course Outlines/Notes: Phil 440 (1978), 442 and 442(II), 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Notebook – Course Outlines Notes: Phil 442(V), 1981-1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Series V: Writings
  - "Symbolic Logic in Descartes and Leibniz," 1940 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Reduction Sentences and Metaphysics" – Offprint, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Correspondence, Early Feedback/Rejections, 1948-1951 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Readers' Reports, 1950-1952 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Contract/Agreements, 1951-1962 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Permissions, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Correspondence, Royalty Reports – University of Chicago Press, 1952-1981 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Preface and Dedication (Typescript), 1953 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Reviews, Response, 1953-1963 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - "On Aristotle's Square of Opposition" – Offprint, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "Logic, Philosophy, and History" – Offprint, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - "What are Law-Statements About?" – Offprint, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - "On Category Differences" – Offprint, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - "Categories" (Encyclopedia of Philosophy) – Correspondence, Typescript, Tear Sheets, 1961-1967 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - The Pragmatic Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Forward to Phoenix Edition (Typescript, Galley, Notes), circa 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Studies in the Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – "Peirce's Experimental Proof of Scholastic Realism" – Manuscript, Typescripts, circa 1963 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Studies in the Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Correspondence, Brochure, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Philosophy (Princeton Studies) – Chisholm, Thompson, et al. – Correspondence, Index, Notes, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Studies in the Philosophy of C. S. Peirce – Reviews, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - "Singular Terms and Intuitions in Kant's Epistemology" – Offprint, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - "Quine and the Inscrutability of Reference" – Offprint, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - "Quine's Theory of Knowledge," Quine's Reply – Typescripts, circa 1977 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - "On A Priori Truth" – Typescript, Proofs, Correspondence (incl. Rorty Comments), Offprint, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - "Epistemic Priority, Analytic Truth, and Naturalized Epistemology" – Offprint, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Abstracts, 1981, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - "Philosophical Approaches to Categories" (Monist) – Typescripts, Notes, Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Referee Reports, Correspondence, Article Draft: Ethics, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Notes and Manuscript Draft – G. H. Mead, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Philosophy and Philosophizing: An Essay on Kant's Epistemology" – Discarded Manuscript Pages [1 of 2], circa 1985 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Philosophy and Philosophizing: An Essay on Kant's Epistemology" – Discarded Manuscript Pages [2 of 2], circa 1985 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Kant's Mathematics – Manuscript, Partial Photocopy, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Brumbaugh Festschrift: Correspondence, Preface, Thompson's Submission, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Unity, Plurality, and the Totality of Kantian Categories" – Draft, Correspondence/Comments, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "Singular Terms and Intuitions in Kant's Epistemology" – Correspondence, Proof, Postscript for Posy Anthology, 1989-1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Abstract and Concrete Description" – Typescript Drafts, Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "Activities, Means, and Agents: Concepts in Philosophy and Science" – Typescript Draft with Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "[Aristotle's] Subject-Predicate Logic" – Manuscript, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "J. S. Mill's Theory of Truth: A Study in Metaphysics and Logic," "On the Distinction between Thing and Property" – Offprints, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - "The Objectivity of Numbers" – Mimeographed Typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "Qualities and Objects" – Manuscript and Typescript Drafts, Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "Reidentifiability" – Manuscript Draft, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "Unity, Plurality, and the Totality of Kantian Categories" –Typescript, Correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Series VI: Writings by Others
  - Allison, Henry – Kant's Theory of Freedom – Typescript [1 of 4], undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Allison, Henry – Kant's Theory of Freedom – Typescript [2 of 4], undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Allison, Henry – Kant's Theory of Freedom – Typescript [3 of 4], undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Allison, Henry – Kant's Theory of Freedom – Typescript [4 of 4], undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Allison, Henry – Guyer Review, Correspondence, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Almeder, Robert: "Peirce's Thirteen Theories of Truth," Hesse Review, "Basic Knowledge and Justification," "Scientific Progress and Peircean Utopian Realism" – Offprints, Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Anonymous: "Secondness, Thirdness, and the Peircean Individual" – Draft for Review, Letter, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Audi, Robert: "A Theory of Practical Reasoning" – Offprint, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Baum, Manfred: "Kant on Cosmological Apperception" – Photocopy, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 11)